A data scientist at Kensho is passionate about one thing: data. The successful candidate will have extensive experience applying a range of econometrics/statistics models to a diverse set of data. You should enjoy moving beyond the theoretic confines of academia to applying your tradecraft in the real world and producing data driven products that will be used by decision makers throughout the global banking industry and beyond. The ideal candidate is precise and detail oriented. Most importantly, a Kenshō data scientist is excited at the opportunity to work in a lean, tight-knit startup bringing transparency to some of the hardest problems on the planet.

What Youll Do:
Conduct original research on some of the most interesting datasets - both proprietary and open source
Identify, research, prototype, and build predictive products
Analyze, transform, structure, and crunch financial data that is growing in size, diversity, and complexity
Write production-ready code to identify interesting outliers, anomalies, correlations, and associations
Write tests to ensure the robustness and reliability of the team's productionized models

What We Look For:
Advanced degree in Computer Science, Statistics, Economics, or related quantitative field
2+ years of experience in data analysis or similar role
At least one core programming expertise, such as python (iPython, NumPy, SciPy, Pandas) or R
Experience with advanced machine learning, natural language process, and statistics model
Strong statistical knowledge and intuition, especially for applying analysis to real data
Strong interest on capital market & economics theory

How to Really Get Our Attention:
Major contributor at a top company with big data
Individual research
Significant experience at a top financial analytics company or hedge fund
Your github account showing entrepreneurial yet practical initiative

Technologies We Like:
Advanced statistics & statistical programming language like python, R, and MATLAB
Python and specifically Numpy, SciPy & Pandas, scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Theano
Data stores like Postgresql, ElasticSearch, and various NoSQL alternatives

Perks:
Medical, Dental, and Vision insurance with 100% premium covered
Unlimited vacation days
Paid Parental Leave
401(k) plan with employer match
Free snacks and drinks
Access to 1 WTC Sky Lobby, discounts at local stores
Citi Bike membership
All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national origin.

kensho.com